<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://eyowo.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://eyowo.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-04T16:30:24+01:00</updated><id>https://eyowo.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Eyowo</title><subtitle>Eyowo is the simplest way to send or recieve money online or offline.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">NACK With Eyowo: Step into the Booth</title><link href="https://eyowo.com/blog/nack-with-eyowo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NACK With Eyowo: Step into the Booth" /><published>2018-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://eyowo.com/blog/nack-with-eyowo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyowo.com/blog/nack-with-eyowo/">&lt;p&gt;Sunday 16th of September was abuzz with activities as NACK (Nigerian Articulate Culture Kullection) Apparel launched its Interlude Kullection, powered by Eyowo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interlude, described as ‘FEARLESS’ was inspired by utilitarianism, consisting of carefully crafted pieces that incorporates pleated and embellished jerseys, edgy military straps and digital art of  native culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Eyowo is created  to be embroidered into the lifestyle of its user, we found this to be a perfect entryway to the smart and feature phones of celebrities such as Sammy Yakubu, Victoria Eze, Praiz, Femi Leye, Ayoola Ayobami, Teddy A, DJ Xclusive and other fashion enthusiasts in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furnished with the Eyowo Experience Booth, we engaged each guest and watched as they re-imagined their phones as payment platforms using Eyowo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it all panned out; After they funded their Eyowo account, each client browsed through the NACK Kullection in display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each guest that interacted with the product stood a chance of winning 1 Samsung s9 and other Samsung accessories. A crowd pleaser was definitely the experience of “paying” for their meals with an actual cowrie. It’s not often technology gets to rub shoulders with an old timer like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relive  the moments below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eyowo-in-action&quot;&gt;Eyowo In Action:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/dara.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/ese1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/shirt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/ese.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack44.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack49.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack41.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;check-out-some-of-your-favourite-celebrities-who-were-in-attendance&quot;&gt;Check out some of your favourite celebrities who were in attendance:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack59.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/ayo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/leye.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack63.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/sam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack69.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;not-even-the-sumptuous-eyowo-cupcakes-and-cookies-were-left-out-&quot;&gt;Not even the sumptuous Eyowo cupcakes and cookies were left out …&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nack/nack02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the NACK X Eyowo partnership was such a huge success which has further triggered our thirst for even more amazing and fun-packed Eyowo events.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aanu Jide-Ojo</name></author><summary type="html">Sunday 16th of September was abuzz with activities as NACK (Nigerian Articulate Culture Kullection) Apparel launched its Interlude Kullection, powered by Eyowo.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting Started On Eyowo</title><link href="https://eyowo.com/blog/getting-started/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Started On Eyowo" /><published>2018-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://eyowo.com/blog/getting-started</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyowo.com/blog/getting-started/">&lt;p&gt;Eyowo provides an easy, convenient and secure way to make and receive payments whether online or offline. 
Everyone who has an active phone number in Nigeria can now make or receive payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-personal-use&quot;&gt;For Personal Use&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Request payments from or make payments to anyone on your phone-book while chatting. Payments can also be authorized through a secure six-digit PIN, a Face ID or a Touch ID.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fund your Eyowo wallet from your debit/credit card, bank deposits or other Eyowo users  or agent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add new beneficiaries and send money from Eyowo to your bank.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay for utility bills such as electricity, Cable TV and other subscriptions seamlessly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Load airtime instantly on your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog/Blog05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started is simple. Download the Eyowo app (on &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.eyowo.android&quot;&gt;Play Store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/ng/app/eyowo/id1353757720?mt=8&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;) and follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ussd&quot;&gt;USSD&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not connected to the internet or you don’t own a smartphone or you simply prefer using USSD for transactions, simply dial *4255# and follow the prompts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog/Blog06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eyowo is fast and widely accessible as it requires no registration or paperwork, all you need is an active phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your credit or debit card details will never be shared with anyone, this reduces the risks for user and ensures privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog/blog07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-business&quot;&gt;For Business&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eyowo offers businesses and their customers a seamless platform through which they can accept and make payments respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just an active phone number, you can now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Receive payments instantly when you use the Eyowo Till app to bill your customers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Monitor the inflow of cash from all your tills as presented in a well-organized, detailed and structured dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deploy the Eyowo Till app to avoid settlement delays and connectivity issues associated with existing infrastructures like P.O.S terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get a customized USSD code through which you can receive payments on your phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blog/Blog08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, your customers no longer have to carry cash around or worry about the slow and hectic process usually witnessed when trying to resolve PoS dispense errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eyowo has flexible features which accommodate simple or complex business models. Our services are currently available across Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eyowo is free for users or merchants who wish to accept payments using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.eyowo.till.android&quot;&gt;Till&lt;/a&gt; app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have got any questions, contact us directly on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/MyEyowo/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MyEyowo&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/myeyowo/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Augustine Ogwo</name></author><summary type="html">Eyowo provides an easy, convenient and secure way to make and receive payments whether online or offline. Everyone who has an active phone number in Nigeria can now make or receive payments.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Within Reach</title><link href="https://eyowo.com/blog/within-reach/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Within Reach" /><published>2018-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://eyowo.com/blog/within-reach</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyowo.com/blog/within-reach/">&lt;p&gt;Mondays are definitely some of the toughest days for Lagosians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s another busy morning in the city that never sleeps. Somewhere in the Victoria Garden City area of Lagos, Cyprian has gotten into his G-Wagon and is navigating his way towards Yaba where he owns a tech start-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just 5:30am, the roads are already busy but the traffic-flow is still smooth. He races through Ikota, Igbo-Efon, Ikate, Marwa, Lekki and now he is approaching the Lekki-toll gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the exact fare lane of Lekki toll, he puts his right hand into the breast-pocket of his well starched and ironed shirt. He removes it and reaches for his trouser’s right pocket and then the left. Seconds later, the car’s glove compartment is wide open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vehicles behind the G-Wagon are composing a hit song with their horns already. The toll attendants are now raining curses on Mr. Cyprian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oga, why you no pass alternative route as you no get money?” the mobile policeman on duty inquires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All these yahoo-boys sef! Na only big car una get,” one LCC staff laments while directing five fingers well spread apart at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprian is short of words but still manages to explain he is up to no tricks. He tries to make a point about how he forgot his wallet at home while rushing out that morning but the blaring horns drown his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr man, leave this place now. You have been saved by the Good samaritan behind you,” an attendant orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he drives away, an embarrassed Cyprian waves at the kind fellow in the Toyota Matrix and the chaos behind him. He can’t understand being so disgraced publicly not because he doesn’t have money but simply because his funds are not within reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crosses himself and says a little prayer while hoping his financial incapacitation doesn’t land him in further trouble this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he descends the Third Mainland bridge, the car’s steering becomes less responsive. A flat tyre?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He drives slowly until he gets to a vulcaniser shop on the Oworonshoki axis of Lagos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oga, abeg help me pump my tyre”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No wahala Sah, na just 200 Naira,” the vulcaniser explained as he removed the valve stem caps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just that I may need to make a transfer to you,” Cyprian responded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ahan oga! You wan transfer 200 Naira?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What I mean is I forgot my wallet at home. I don’t have any cash or card on me,” a distraught Cyprian tried to explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No wahala oga, you don hear about Eyowo before?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oga, just dial *4255# on top your phone make I show you”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Cyprian slides his phone out of his tight pants, the vulcanizer kicks the tyre one more time; his own way of gauging pressure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Augustine Ogwo</name></author><summary type="html">Mondays are definitely some of the toughest days for Lagosians.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enter Your PIN</title><link href="https://eyowo.com/blog/enter-your-pin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enter Your PIN" /><published>2018-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://eyowo.com/blog/enter-your-pin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyowo.com/blog/enter-your-pin/">&lt;p&gt;If you have ever been to a Nigerian ATM, you have probably witnessed one, some or all of these kind of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-figured-out&quot;&gt;All Figured Out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ones always look very confident. As soon as they step up to the ATM, they clear their throats and begin to punch all the keys. 15 minutes after, they are still at it. At this point, you hear someone from the queue scream out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Abeg, if you no know wetin you dey do, make person help you o!”
Too proud to acknowledge that he/she can’t go about their business properly, the person at the ATM looks towards the person complaining with pride-filled eyes before saying “Oya come na”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;atm-ghosts&quot;&gt;ATM Ghosts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know those who appear at the ATM queue, make a simple remark, disappear and only reappear several minutes later to a secure position on the queue.
These are the ones who come to the queue just to tell you that they are behind you and then they disappear. Just when you have almost forgotten they exist, they show up to cause even more commotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;big-money-spenders&quot;&gt;Big Money Spenders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the people who spend a lot of time at the ATM. Just when you think they are done, they pull out a second and maybe third ATM card.
At this point, those at the bottom of the queue have either started grumbling or cursing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hungry-atms&quot;&gt;Hungry ATMs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the worst of all. Has the ATM ever retained or ‘swallowed’ your debit card on a Friday evening? Be ready for a hellish weekend if this happens to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;illiterate-cards&quot;&gt;Illiterate Cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can one stand on a queue for over an hour and forty-five minutes and then receive the ‘Card Is Not Smart’ prompt afterwards?
Indeed, life isn’t fair at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prepare-to-be-well-beaten&quot;&gt;Prepare To Be Well Beaten&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most banks care about your money but do they care so much about you? When you join that ATM queue, it is either the sun serves you a heavy blow or the rain beats the hell out of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;that-emotional-moment&quot;&gt;That Emotional Moment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are leaving the ATM queue, you can feel your phone beep more than once. Yeah, nothing more heart wrenching than making a withdrawal and being debited multiple times.
You feel even worse when you realize you have to file a report and it might take a number of working days before it is even actioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-atm-keepers&quot;&gt;The ATM Keepers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ones can bring their duvet to the ATM. When it’s time to punch in their PIN, they open their arms and then move left, right and left again like goalkeepers warming up to catch a penalty.
Even when no one is next to them, they just keep looking over their shoulders. Not even the loud hisses from the others on the queue deters them from safeguarding their fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-famous-ones&quot;&gt;The ‘Famous’ Ones&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know those who try to jump the ATM queue and when they get checked, you hear something like “Do you know who I am”?
Don’t even bother asking that person who he/she is because in reality, the person is only going to stutter and utter gibberish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;those-on-excursion&quot;&gt;Those On Excursion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have probably seen those people who get to the ATM and then pose like they are in front of a mirror.
It takes them 7 minutes to punch in their PIN, another 5 minutes to  check their account balance and forever to withdraw ₦1000. Then, they go through the same process to withdraw another ₦1000 and another. Don’t curse, let the person enjoy his/her turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-foster-parents&quot;&gt;Your Foster Parents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ones just ignore the queue and walk towards the ATM. Don’t bother questioning them because they are older and this is Africa. If you think you know your rights too much and you dare question them, you will hear something similar to this: “I’m old enough to be your father” or “Children of nowadays”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;•••&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;but-do-you-know-you-can-avoid-these-issues-by-simply-dialing-4255-you-can-also-download-eyowo-on-app-store-or-play-store&quot;&gt;But do you know you can avoid these issues by simply dialing *4255#? You can also download Eyowo on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/eyowo/id1353757720?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.eyowo.android&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Play Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Augustine Ogwo</name></author><summary type="html">If you have ever been to a Nigerian ATM, you have probably witnessed one, some or all of these kind of people.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Big Parcel</title><link href="https://eyowo.com/blog/the-bigger-parcel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Big Parcel" /><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://eyowo.com/blog/the-bigger-parcel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eyowo.com/blog/the-bigger-parcel/">&lt;p&gt;“When he hears someone is going to the village, he buys a wrapper. Inside that wrapper he wants to send to his mother, he will hide some money inside it” .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you grew up or live in Nigeria, you have probably heard or been part of a similar conversation such as the one above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever think deeply of the fate of your relatives in the villages? You know those relatives and friends in your hometown who do not have access to smartphones, banks or financial institutions? 
Do you know someone who has never had a bank account in their entire life? For such people, all transactions are cash and carry. How can one send money to those relatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if that money is tampered with before it gets to her? What if the gift containing raw cash gets lost in transit?
Sometimes, advising people to open a bank account is synonymous to flogging a dead horse. It is often not due to a lack of willingness on their part but rather the unavailability of banking infrastructures in a lot of communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a Jumia Report released in March 2018, Nigeria with an estimated 193 million population, has 162 million mobile subscriptions.
Statistics from the Nigerian Inter-Bank Settlement System (NIBSS) also show that they were only 41. 3 million linked BVN accounts as at 2017.
From the above statistics, it is easy to deduce that a lot of Nigerians who have access to mobile phones do not own bank accounts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever imagined a world where everyone with a phone number irrespective of them being banked or unbanked can pay and receive money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t imagine for too long, that world exists already. Experience Eyowo &lt;a href=&quot;https://eyowo.com/experience/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Augustine Ogwo</name></author><summary type="html">“When he hears someone is going to the village, he buys a wrapper. Inside that wrapper he wants to send to his mother, he will hide some money inside it” .</summary></entry></feed>